Swapnil More

swapnilmore@iisc.ac.in | swapnil2me.github.io | +91-91139-99596

Skype:- live:swapnil2me | Gmail:- swapnil2me@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Ph.D.

Nanoelectromechanical Systems IISc Bangalore Aug 2022

CGPA: 7/10

M.Tech Nanotechnology IISc Bangalore June 2016

CGPA: 6.4/8

BE Mechanical University of Pune June 2012
Grade: 69%

Diploma Mechanical Government Polytechnic Pune June 2012 Grade: 86%

CERTIFICATION

Machine Learning (Stanford Online)

SKILLS

Nanotechnology

E-beam Lithography, RIE, DRIE, SEM, AFM, Electrical Characterization of FETs

Data Science

Hypothesis testing, Model fitting, Machine Learning

Programming

Python, JavaScript, MATLAB, LabVIEW, Mathematica

Web Development

HTML, CSS, D3Js, React, Django, Flask.

Mechanical Eng.

Solid Mechanics, Machine Design, Nonlinear dynamics

Design Tools

CATIA, AutoCAD, COMSOL

PROFILE

I am an interdisciplinary engineer with a keen interest in Data Science and Machine Learning. I have core expertise in Mechanical Engineering and Nanotechnology. I love solving problems that push the limits of my knowledge and skills.

CURRENT ROLE

Research Scholar

NEMS Lab, Centre for Nano Science and Engineering, IISc Bangalore. (Aug 2015 – Present)

Project: Nonlinear dynamics and strain engineering of 2D nanoelectromechanical systems (NEMS).

- Design and implement NEMS fabrication.
- Set up scientific experiments to actuate and detect resonance in NEMS using Signal Generators, Lock-In amplifiers, Spectrum Analyzers; design experiments for specific testing; designing PCB and RF circuits for custom needs.
- Analyzing experimental data to extract system behavior; Modeling nonlinear behavior of NEMS using statistical regression techniques.
- Writing application software for instrument control, data acquisition, and data analysis (Python, JavaScript, MATLAB).

PAST EXPERIENCE

Senior Project Assistant IIT Bombay. (July 2013 – Nov 2013)

• Logistics and administrative support to the project.

Graduate Engineer Trainee (Sales & Dealer Development) Mahindra Navistar Automotive Ltd. (Aug 2012 – Jan 2013)

• Conducting market surveys to understand customer requirements in the LCV segment; Organizing meetings between customers and financial service providers for boosting product sales; Developing sales executive's skills by designing product manuals and sales checklists.

PUBLICATIONS

- Strain engineering of graphene nano-resonator, <u>J. Micromech.</u> <u>Microeng. 31 045015, 2021</u>
- Ultra-sensitive charge detection and latch memory using MoS2-nanoresonator-based bifurcation amplifiers, Appl. Phys. Lett. 118, 053105 (2021)
- Fabrication of 2D NEMS on Flexible Substrates for Strain Engineering in Sensing Applications, <u>IWPSD 2017. Springer Proceedings in Physics, vol 215. Springer, Cham</u>

Projects Finished

Nanotechnology	Skills Learned
Fabrication of NEMS / 2D FETs on flexible PET substrate for strain engineering. Study of electronic properties and gas sensing behavior of mono, bi, tri-layer MoS2 under application of uniaxial strain. Design 4-point bending machine to strain NEMS device.	E-beam Lithography, RIE, DRIE, SEM, AFM, characterization of FETs, Machine design
Design of PCB with vacuum cavity for actuation and detection of resonance in 2D NEMS / FETs fabricated on thin Silicon Diaphragm which can be deformed by applying air pressure for strain tuning of the NEMS	PCB Design (Eagle), Vacuum system design
Computer Engineering	
Web app for Scientific Experiments Python library for instrument control using PyVisa and VXIII Flask server for remote control of scientific experiments Dashboard to monitor the experiment results	loT; Python: NumPy, Pandas, Flask, REST API design; JavaScript, D3.js, Chart.js
ChatLab: A smart <u>chatbot</u> that simulates basic quantum circuits and solves nonlinear differential equations on the fly.	Qiskit
Modelling Nonlinear Dynamics of NEMS with tunable nonlinearities. Numerical integration scheme to solve for the temporal response of the nonlinear dynamical system. The simulations allowed evaluating the behavior of a highly nonlinear system in multi-parameter space.	SciPy, Numerical Methods
Microscope Automation Arduino controlled X-Y stage for a microscope to scan the test surface under microscope, process and analyze scan images for desired features, and return the X-Y coordinates of detected features on the test surface	Computer Vision, MATLAB
Ethereum DAPPS: A simple <u>payments app</u> and its extension to <u>rent out IoTs</u> on Ganache test net.	Blockchain
Mechanical Engineering	
Development of TE mode cell for measurement of electromagnetic emissions and testing radiation immunity of integrated circuits.	Testing DUTs for electromagnetic compatibility
Design of a six-speed reduction gearbox for tool room lathe of 406 x 762 mm capacity. Design of a single plate clutch for automotive application.	CAD, Machine Design
Pneumatic automation using a programmable logic controller (PLC).	Pneumatic Actuator Design, PLC